[
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Arithmetic Operators in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "To compare values",
            "To perform mathematical calculations",
            "To assign values",
            "To combine the multiple conditions."
        ],
        "answer": "To perform mathematical calculations"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main purpose of Relational Operators?",
        "options": [
            "To combine the multiple conditions.",
            "To perform arithmetic operations",
            "To compare two values and return Boolean.",
            "To repeat statements"
        ],
        "answer": "To compare two values and return Boolean."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Logical Operators in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "To compare values",
            "To perform mathematical operations",
            "To combine multiple conditions",
            "To assign values"
        ],
        "answer": "To combine multiple conditions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Assignment Operators?",
        "options": [
            "To compare values",
            "To assign values to variables",
            "To check conditions",
            "To combine multiple conditions"
        ],
        "answer": "To assign values to variables"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the Ternary Operator (?:)?",
        "options": [
            "To combine the multiple conditions.",
            "To store the value in variables.",
            "To write multiple conditions",
            "To make decisions in a single line."
        ],
        "answer": "To make decisions in a single line."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the correct syntax of ternary operator?",
        "options": [
            "condition : exp1 ? exp2",
            "condition ? exp1 : exp2",
            "if ? else : condition",
            "condition ?? exp1 : exp2"
        ],
        "answer": "condition ? exp1 : exp2"
    },
    {
        "question": "User can login only if username AND password are correct.Which operator should be used?",
        "options": [
            "||",
            "==",
            "&&",
            "="
        ],
        "answer": "&&"
    },
    {
        "question": "User can login using email OR mobile number.Which operator is suitable?",
        "options": [
            "&&",
            "||",
            "!=",
            ">="
        ],
        "answer": "||"
    },
    {
        "question": "New password should not be equal to old password. Which operator is required?",
        "options": [
            "==",
            "=",
            "!=",
            "&&"
        ],
        "answer": "!="
    },
    {
        "question": "To calculate total bill amount by adding item price to total price repeatedly.Which operator is best?",
        "options": [
            "+",
            "+=",
            "*",
            "++"
        ],
        "answer": "+="
    },
    {
        "question": "To display “Eligible” or “Not Eligible” based on age in one line, which operator is best?",
        "options": [
            "&&",
            "||",
            "?:",
            "=="
        ],
        "answer": "?:"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of a Compound / Complex Assignment operator in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Directly assign a value to a variable",
            "Assign the result of an expression to a variable",
            "Compare two values",
            "Increase the value by 1"
        ],
        "answer": "Assign the result of an expression to a variable"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following demonstrates Not a real requirement of addition?",
        "options": [
            "let sum = 100 + 200;",
            "let totalMarks = maths + science + social;",
            "let totalSalary = basic + hra + allowance;",
            "let netAmount = totalAmount + taxAmount + deliveryFee;"
        ],
        "answer": "let sum = 100 + 200;"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct order of operator precedence in JavaScript from highest to lowest?",
        "options": [
            "() → * / % → + - → =",
            "* / % → () → + - → =",
            "() → + - → * / % → =",
            "+ - → * / % → () → ="
        ],
        "answer": "() → * / % → + - → ="
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the following expression? 6 + 6 * (6 + 6) / 6 - 6 % 6",
        "options": [
            "12",
            "18",
            "24",
            "36"
        ],
        "answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operator is used to combine or concatenate strings in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "*",
            "+",
            "**",
            "%"
        ],
        "answer": "+"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the following code? let name = \"Ratan\"; console.log(\"Hi\" + 10 + 5 + name + (20 + 30));",
        "options": [
            "\"Hi105Ratan50\"",
            "\"Hi15Ratan50\"",
            "\"Hi105Ratan2030\"",
            "\"Hi105Ratan20+30\""
        ],
        "answer": "\"Hi105Ratan50\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the operator used to calculate power exponentiation in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "*",
            "^",
            "**",
            "%"
        ],
        "answer": "**"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation will the second condition of && be executed?",
        "options": [
            "When the first condition is false",
            "When both conditions are false",
            "When the first condition is true",
            "Always second condition executed."
        ],
        "answer": "When the first condition is true"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation will the second condition of || be executed?",
        "options": [
            "When the first condition is false",
            "When both conditions are false",
            "When the first condition is true",
            "Always second condition executed."
        ],
        "answer": "When the first condition is false"
    }
]